<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Techniques | Montree Bungnasang]]></title>
  <link href="http://gailo22.github.io/blog/categories/techniques/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://gailo22.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-23T16:51:15+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://gailo22.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[gailo22]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[gailo22@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Polya's Problem Solving Techniques]]></title>
    <link href="http://gailo22.github.io/blog/2014/03/12/polyas-problem-solving-techniques/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-12T11:07:26+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://gailo22.github.io/blog/2014/03/12/polyas-problem-solving-techniques</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In 1945 George Polya published the book How To Solve It which quickly became
his most prized publication. It sold over one million copies and has been translated
into 17 languages. In this book he identifies four basic principles of problem solving.</p>

<h2>Polya&rsquo;s First Principle: Understand the problem</h2>

<p>This seems so obvious that it is often not even mentioned, yet studens are often
stymied in their efforts to solve problems simply because they don&rsquo;t understand it
fully, or even in part. Polya taught teachers to ask students questions such as:</p>

<ul>
<li>Do you understand all the words used in stating the problem?</li>
<li>What are you asked to find or show?</li>
<li>Can you restate the problem in your own words?</li>
<li>Can you think of a picture or diagram that might help you understand the
problem?</li>
<li>Is there enough information to enable you to find a solution?</li>
</ul>


<h2>Polya&rsquo;s Second Principle: Devise a plan</h2>

<p>Polya mentions that there are many reasonable ways to solve problems. The skill
at choosing an appropriate strategy is best learned by solving many problems. You
will find choosing a strategy increasingly easy. A partial list of strategies is included:</p>

<ul>
<li>Guess and check</li>
<li>Look for a pattern</li>
<li>Make an orderly list</li>
<li>Draw a picture</li>
<li>Eliminate possibilities</li>
<li>Solve a simpler problem</li>
<li>Use symmetry</li>
<li>Use a model</li>
<li>Consider special cases</li>
<li>Work backwards</li>
<li>Use direct reasoning</li>
<li>Use a formula</li>
<li>Solve an equation</li>
<li>Be ingenious</li>
</ul>


<h2>Polya&rsquo;s Third Principle: Carry out the plan</h2>

<p>This step is usually easier than devising the plan. In general, all you need is
care and patience, given that you have the necessary skills. Persist with the plan that
you have chosen. If it continues not to work discard it and choose another. Don&rsquo;t be
misled, this is how mathematics is done, even by professionals.</p>

<h2>Polya&rsquo;s Fourth Principle: Look back</h2>

<p>Polya mentions that much can be gained by taking the time to re
ect and look back at what you have done, what worked, and what didn&rsquo;t. Doing this will enable
you to predict what strategy to use to solve future problems.</p>

<p>So starting on the next page, here is a summary, in the master&rsquo;s own words, on
strategies for attacking problems in mathematics class. This is taken from the book,
<em>How To Solve It, by George Polya, 2nd ed., Princeton University Press, 1957, ISBN
0-691-08097-6.</em></p>

<h2>1. UNDERSTAND THE PROBLEM</h2>

<ul>
<li><strong>First.</strong> You have to understand the problem.</li>
<li>What is the unknown? What are the data? What is the condition?</li>
<li>Is it possible to satisfy the condition? Is the condition sufficient to determine the unknown? Or is it insuffcient? Or redundant? Or contradictory?</li>
<li>Draw a figure. Introduce suitable notation.</li>
<li>Separate the various parts of the condition. Can you write them down?</li>
</ul>


<h2>2. DEVISING A PLAN</h2>

<ul>
<li><strong>Second.</strong> Find the connection between the data and the unknown. You
may be obliged to consider auxiliary problems if an immediate connection
cannot be found. You should obtain eventually a plan of the solution.</li>
<li>Have you seen it before? Or have you seen the same problem in a slightly
different form?</li>
<li>Do you know a related problem? Do you know a theorem that could be
useful?</li>
<li>Look at the unknown! Try to think of a familiar problem having the same
or a similar unknown.</li>
<li>Here is a problem related to yours and solved before. Could you use it?
Could you use its result? Could you use its method? Should you introduce
some auxiliary element in order to make its use possible?</li>
<li>Could you restate the problem? Could you restate it still differently? Go
back to definitions.</li>
<li>If you cannot solve the proposed problem, try to solve first some related
problem. Could you imagine a more accessible related problem? A more
general problem? A more special problem? An analogous problem? Could
you solve a part of the problem? Keep only a part of the condition, drop
the other part; how far is the unknown then determined, how can it vary?
Could you derive something useful from the data? Could you think of
other data appropriate to determine the unknown? Could you change the
unknown or data, or both if necessary, so that the new unknown and the
new data are nearer to each other?</li>
<li>Did you use all the data? Did you use the whole condition? Have you
taken into account all essential notions involved in the problem?</li>
</ul>


<h2>3. CARRYING OUT THE PLAN</h2>

<ul>
<li><strong>Third.</strong> Carry out your plan.</li>
<li>Carrying out your plan of the solution, check each step. Can you see clearly
that the step is correct? Can you prove that it is correct?</li>
</ul>


<h2>4. LOOKING BACK</h2>

<ul>
<li><strong>Fourth.</strong> Examine the solution obtained.</li>
<li>Can you check the result? Can you check the argument?</li>
<li>Can you derive the solution differently? Can you see it at a glance?</li>
<li>Can you use the result, or the method, for some other problem?</li>
</ul>


<p>ref: <sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup></p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>http://math.berkeley.edu/~gmelvin/math110sp14/polya.pdf<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
